JITESH SHEWALE

ishewale3690@gmail.com

ishewale3690@gmail.com

+91 8446195953

Mumbai, India

in linkedin/jitesh

github/jitesh

Profile

I have been working as an Informatica MDM Developer at TCS for the past 1.9 years, where I implemented master data management solutions using Informatica tools and Python shell scripts. Since 2019, I have been actively exploring Python, SQL, Django, and Data Science through various online resources. I am highly interested in pursuing further opportunities and given the chance, I am enthusiastic about delving deeper into the realms of Data Science and ML.

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, JavaScript, Unix commands

Python Libraries

Os, Pandas, Scikit-learn, NLTK, Pyspark, Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Selenium

Web Development

Flask and Django (JINJA2 templating, MVC , ORM), HTML/CSS $\,$

Databases and Others

SQLite/DB2, Data Struct. and Algo, OOP

Other Tools

VS Studio, PyCharm, SublimeText, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, DevOps, Postman API, Informatica

Certificates

- Data-Structure Michigan University, Coursera
- Django Masterclass, Udemy
- Data Analysis with Python by IBM, Coursera
- Machine Learning with Python by IBM, Coursera
- Advanced SQL Retrieval Queries Coursera
- · Spark and Python for Big Data, Udemy

Awards

Gold in competitive programming *☑* on *Hacker-rank*

Secured 277th rank in National Coding Competition

organized by Coding Ninja, 2020

Education

BE (Electronics & Telecomm.)

RAIT, Nerul. Mumbai University

2017 - 2021

CGPA - 9.11

HSC (12th)

C.H.M College, Ulhasnagar-Thane 2015 – 2017

84.77%

Professional Experience

Informatica-Python Developer

Tata Consultancy Services, Mumbai

2021 - present

- Created business rules in Informatica Developer and imported them to Informatica power center to load the standardized and good format of data to staging tables.
- Created references tables, mappletes, applications and workflows and deployed that to Data integration service for further execution of workflow.
- Configured Search Strategy, Match rule sets, Match Columns for Match and Merge Process in improving data quality by match analysis
- Developed and maintained Python ETL scripts to scrape the data and load the data into database.
- Automated different workflows, which are initiated manually with python script and unix shell scripting.
- Written code for various Python transformations to apply the business rules on input data from heterogeneous sources.
- Written various Python scripts to validate the business rules and constraints. Enriched the business data by writing various cleansing and standardization methods.
- Generated various reports by connecting to databases, written elaborate queries to extract necessary information.

Self Learning

2019 - present

- Developed front and backend using python Django web framework.
- Implemented MVC architecture in developing the web application with the help of Django Framework.
- Implemented code to perform CRUD operation Django.
- Designed user interactive front end web pages using web techs HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript.
- Deployed the project into Heroku using GIT version control system.
- Managed, performed data processing and cleaning on large dataset using pandas and sqlite.
- Built various graphs which provides insights to available business dataset using python matplotlib library.
- Wrote python automation testing using selenium web driver across chrome, edge browser.

Projects

Calorie Tracker ☑ *Django and Bootstrap*

Rest API for Books data

Diango rest framework

Loan Elibility prediction ☑ *ML*, *Python*

Office Data analysis 🛭

Student Data Analysis

using Pyspark

using Pyspark